<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Andrew Bibian</title>
    <link>https://bibsian.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Andrew Bibian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 18:44:44 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bibsian.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bayes Rule - An Example with Code</title>
      <link>https://bibsian.github.io/posts/bayes-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 18:44:44 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bibsian.github.io/posts/bayes-rule/</guid>
      <description>In the interests of learning and developing a better sense on how to to use Bayes Rule we&amp;rsquo;re going to do two things in this post.
We&amp;rsquo;re going use Bayes Rules to come up with an analytical solution to a probability problem (like you&amp;rsquo;d see in an interview setting). And
We&amp;rsquo;ll simulate some data to see if we can approximate an analytical solution (to help develop our programming chops). The Scenario Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re a patient who has just received a positive test result for HIV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Normal Equation: Part 1 - Formulating the Cost Function</title>
      <link>https://bibsian.github.io/posts/normal-equation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:06:54 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bibsian.github.io/posts/normal-equation/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never found a blog post that truly made me understand how to derive the normal equation. I think a reason for this is a lot of authors have their own perspective on the problem, leading to a mental image I can&amp;rsquo;t quite grasp onto. But having grappled with linear algebra for a bit, I think I&amp;rsquo;m ready to try my hand at writing a series of posts that helps someone like my former self understand such an equation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Jupyter Notebooks on the Jetson Nano (via https)</title>
      <link>https://bibsian.github.io/posts/jupyter-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 13:44:36 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bibsian.github.io/posts/jupyter-setup/</guid>
      <description>Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to configure Jupyter notebooks so we can connect to our Nano over https. Note, this same logic could easily be applied to a server in the cloud.
Prereqs/Assumptions You will be doing this for Python3
You already have your default python3 configured for virtualenvs
You have created a virtualenv that we&amp;rsquo;ll install Jupyter &amp;amp; the Ipython kernel on.
We&amp;rsquo;re doing this setup while we are sshed into the Nano (ssh &amp;lt;jetson name&amp;gt;@&amp;lt;jetson_ip&amp;gt;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring the Jetson Nano</title>
      <link>https://bibsian.github.io/posts/jetson-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 20:37:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bibsian.github.io/posts/jetson-setup/</guid>
      <description>Background If you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard of Nvidia&amp;rsquo;s Jetson Nano you can think of it as a Raspberry Pi with a built-in GPU; their developer community page has some pretty interesting projects if you&amp;rsquo;d like to learn more.
Now, you&amp;rsquo;re only going to get some milage out of the rest of this post if you&amp;rsquo;ve already setup your Jetson Nano hardware. I set mine up to use the barrel jack for a power source, added a wifi card to the board, and connected it to the Raspberry Pi camera (to collect training data and use for real-time inference).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://bibsian.github.io/posts/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 19:53:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bibsian.github.io/posts/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Hello,
My name is Andrew Bibian and welcome to my site! Also, thanks for coming. 😃
I created this site to help myself learn how to write better and explore concepts in data science and deep learning. That was around 2019 and after I started writing posts, it petered out fairly quickly. But it&amp;rsquo;s now 2022 and I&amp;rsquo;m taking a different approach to how I document my various life learnings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
